# Pavan Parvathaneni

## **Network Engineer - Athene Annuity and Life Company**

Ackworth, IA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Pavan-Parvathaneni/e6b9f7c3d48d310f

Professional experience over 6 years in the Networking Design and Management

- > Experience in Networking and Security, including hands-on experience in providing network support, installation and analysis for a broad range of LAN / WAN/MAN communication systems.
- > Configured Cisco 2500, 2600, 3000, 6500, 7500, 7200 Series routers.
- ➤ Configured Cisco Catalyst 2960, 3750, 4500, 6500 and Nexus 3000, 5000, 6000, 7000, 9000 series switches.
- > Designing and implementing different types of VPN technologies including IPSEC, GRE, and MPLS for secure remote access.
- > Switched telephone network (PSTN), PPP, ISDN, Frame Relay, TCP/IP, and VPN.
- > Experienced in configuring protocols HSRP, GLBP, VRRP, ICMP, IGMP, PPP, HDLC, PAP, CHAP and SNMP.
- > Performed IOS upgrades on CISCO routers and Switches.
- > Strong gasp of current and future technologies including TCP/IP, IPv4/v6, RIP, EIGRP, OSPF, BGP, Frame Relay, ACL, VPN, Wireless LAN and configuration of VLANS.
- > Proficient in operation of Cisco Nexus 7K switches with Fabric Extender using VPC, VLAN, STP and LACP.
- > Implementation of DHCP, DNS, FTP, TFTP, Frame Relay, MPLS, ATM, ISDN.
- > Used tools like Excel, MS-VISIO to perform professional level documentation.
- > Experience in Network Monitoring Systems Solar winds and Wire shark.
- > Switching technologies include VLAN, STP, TRUNKING, VTP, PVST, RSTP, and MSTP.
- > Managing IP traffic with Access-Lists, Network with NAT and PAT.
- > Experience in working with VRF aware Routing Protocols RIP, EIGRP, OSPF& BGP.
- > Knowledge on configuration & maintenance of UMUX (Multiplexer).
- > Experience in SDH/ MPLS / ISP / VSAT / Nx64 / DCN / MEN / Switch technologies and other telecom technologies.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Network Engineer**

Athene Annuity and Life Company - April 2016 to Present

Responsibilities

- > Responsible for implementing various existing network technologies, integration of new networking technologies and providing level 2 support.
- > Network provisioning for the new circuit or existing circuit.
- > Worked on 2600, 3500 series, 7609 and Juniper M7i routers.
- > Preparing detailed Incident Reports for the issues faced by the customer on request from the customer or the product managers
- > Technical assistance for LAN/WAN management and complex customer issues.
- > Configured switch for 802.1x port based authentication.
- > Implemented port aggregation & link negotiation using LACP and PAGP.

- > Used distribute lists, route-maps & administrative distance, offset-lists for route re-distribution and route updates.
- > Configured PVSTP+ for loop prevention and VTP for Inter-VLAN Routing.
- > Creation and Administration of VLAN and Inter VLAN Routing in Switches.
- > Taking backup and up gradation of Flash for Routers, Switches using TFTP server and Password Recovery.
- > Configured EIGRP and BGP on routers.
- > Quickly resolve all IP network issues to reduce waste and downtime while also ensuring client service.
- > Work with circuit provisioning team and with access vendors to deliver new circuits or access trunks. Forecast the core capacity requirements in an environment when demand is constantly growing.
- > Experience on Configuration and Maintenance of MPBGP for L3VPN and L2VPN, IPSec VPN for corporate customer's data solution.
- > VLAN configuration to differentiate applications with RPVST & HSRP.
- > MPLS configuration between the company branches with routing protocols.
- > IP Allocation for all applications and servers and other needs throughout organization.

## **Network Engineer**

Blue Cross & Blue Shield - February 2015 to March 2016

Responsibilities

- > Part of the team for LAN/WAN maintenance which includes assigning IP addresses, designing, installation, configuration, testing etc.
- > Implementation and troubleshooting of DHCP, TCP/IP, UDP in wide area networks.
- > Involved in implementing Cisco Layer 3 switches 3750, 4500, 6500 in multi VLAN environment with the use of inter-VLAN routing, ISL trunk, ether channel.
- > Configured Rapid per VLAN Spanning Tree Protocol (RPVST+) for loop prevention and VTP for Inter-VLAN Routing.
- > Configured OSPF and BGP in routers.
- > Active team member in planning and scheduling for Deployment of Network Components, and IOS up grades.
- > Configuring, Managing & Monitoring Cisco Switches as a core & access switches.
- > Implementing Inter-vlan Routing on Layer2 & Layer3 switches and Layer2 security features (Port Security, 802.1X) S in a switched network.
- > Using TACAS Server, Cisco works, Kiwi cat tool for Network Management.
- > Publishing weekly network dashboards, reporting out network uptime, network utilization which would assist the management in making future decisions about network ramp up.
- > Configured Access List ACL (Std., Ext, and Named) to provide accessibility to users for different applications and restrict unauthorized users.
- > Used INFOBLOX for DHCP to automatically assign IP addresses to DHCP clients.

#### **Network Engineer**

TULIP Telecom - September 2012 to November 2014

Responsibilities

- > Evaluate network trouble tickets escalated by Helpdesk Engineers to determine nature of the problem, develop course of action, and follow through to successful resolution.
- > Troubleshooting and diagnosing the exact cause of the problem and taking necessary steps to avoid the reoccurrence of the issue.
- > Troubleshooting of MPLS / L2 / VPN circuits.
- > Determine when a hardware-related problem requires on-site field service dispatch.

- > Maintain contact with field support engineers to ensure that repair procedures are followed and updates customer with status of field repairs.
- > Provide timely and accurate updates in the trouble ticket database.
- > Provide phone support directly to customers experiencing network performance issues.
- > Configuring routing on client end routers and PE routers as per client's request.
- > Configuration of L2 and MPLS circuits if required.
- > Providing remote assistance to field engineers.
- > Adding Customer circuits under MRTG monitoring.
- > Monitoring links for premium customer of all the region & Proactively monitoring clients HO links and critical sites.
- > Opening of fault tickets for affected circuits and tracking down the issue; restoring the link in coordination with the respected team.
- > Escalating the calls to the respective regions higher-up's and team members and updating clients on the regular basis and briefing them on the developments.
- > Creating client's monthly downtime/uptime reports & creating preventive and corrective actions reports for the SLA breached issues.
- > Updating and Maintaining Database details in Circuit Id's (as Radio IP's, Bandwidth, Client details & etc.).
- > Following up with customers for commercial clearance & updating the account managers.

## Jr. Network Engineer

Beam Telecom - March 2011 to August 2012

Responsibilities

- > Installation and configuration of Cisco Switches, Network devices.
- > Documentation for any Network related incidents.
- > Implementation, Maintaining and Troubleshooting Lan and Wan network.
- > Creating Access-list as per requirement.
- > Responsible for designing and implementation of customers' network infrastructure.
- > Installation of checkpoint and Maintenance in a distributed environment.
- > IOS up gradation of Cisco Routers and Switches.
- > Scaling the network with NAT and PAT.
- > Follow-up with Service Providers and vendors for complaints.
- > Firewall rule set changes as per client requirements.
- > Implemented traffic filters using Standard and Extended access-lists
- > Taking Monthly backups of all Devices using Cisco Works.
- > Participate in LAN/WAN network planning activities.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Master's in Computers Information Systems in Computers Information Systems

New England College

**SKILLS** 

BGP (2 years), Cisco (2 years), EIGRP (1 year), LAN (3 years), VLAN (2 years)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Technical Skills

Routers Cisco 2600, 3600, 3800, 7200, 7600 and Juniper M7i router series
Cisco Catalyst Switches 2960, 3750, 4500, and 6500 and Nexus 2K/5K/7K/9k series
LAN Technologies Ethernet Standards, VLAN, Inter-VLAN, VTP, STP, RSTP, SMTP, Ether Channel, Port Fast, ACL, Light weight access points
WAN Technologies Frame relay, (E1/T1/E3/T3) lines, PPP, HDLC, DS3, OC192
Routing Protocols RIP V1/V2, EIGRP, OSPF, BGP, Static Routing, Summarization
Gateway Redundancy HSRP, VRRP, GLBP, Ether channel technology (LACP, PAgP)
Network Management Tools Wireshark, Net flow Analyzer, IBM Netcool
Applications MS Office, MS Visio 2010

Operating Systems Windows (98, 2000, XP, 7), Linux